Vladimir Lenin or Joseph Stalin was from
Владимир Ленин или Иосиф Сталин был из
this family the last the last
этого рода последний последним
ruler from this family Romano Who was well in
правителем из этого из рода Романо Кто
my opinion Lenin I don't know Lenin Yes I
был ну по-моему Ленин не знаю Ленин Да
understand well he is Vladimir Ilyich Lenin Yes
понял ну он же Владимир Ильич Ленин Да
it is Lenin - it is his nickname like a
это ж Ленин - это его кличка типа
party one And so he was Vladimir
партийная так А так он был Владимир
Romanov Yeah from Ulyanovsk Yes they knew
Романов Угу из Ульяновска Да это знали
or guessed it is obvious by what Well obviously not
или угадали очевидно по что Ну явно не
Stalin hello about you 18 years old yes yes well what is that
Сталин здравствуйте о вам 18 лет
flag on the
есть есть а ну что за прапор на
wall Well what do you think I don't know
стене Ну а что как вы думаете не знаю
maybe either Imperial or
может або Имперский або
Ukrainian Well here and what do you think I don't
украинский Ну вот а вы какой думаете не
know you are from Bitki Now a second Wait do
знаю ты с битки Сейчас секунду Подождите
you see me no no now I am not for you a
ты видишь меня нет нет сейчас я не вам
second and you you are Streamer Yes Streamer yes
секунду а вы вы Стример Да Стример да
Streamer Well that's good That's good And you are
Стример Ну это хорошо Это хорошо А вы
not swearing here you just see the flag
здесь не ругаетесь просто видите фла
Imperial you see I understand me not I am
Имперский видите я же понимаю мно не мне
interested then Turn on the light I
интересно то Включите Свет я с человеком
will talk to the man with the imperial flag I am
с имперским флагом поговорю мне
interested why are you talking to me it is
интересно зачем со мной говорите по там
written there We are Russians with us God
же вас написано Мы русские с нами бог Да
shine
посвети
[music]
[музыка]
er, code,
еру кода
here was the flag of the Romanov emperors, yeah,
вот был флаг э императоров Романовых да
yeah, yeah, who were the Romanovs, can you
Угу Да кто такие Романовы были не
tell me? They were rulers. They were a
подскажете это были правители это была
family, like rich, I think they were rich, I
семья типа богатая по-моему богатая я
didn't study history, I have a community,
историю не учил у меня сообщество
more or less, not rich, like, m,
более-менее не богатая типа м из этого
like, there were a lot of rulers from this family, yeah,
рода типа было очень много правителей
got it. But let's do it this way. Vladimir
Угу понял А вот Э давайте так э Владимир
Lenin or Joseph Stalin was from this
Ленин или Иосиф Сталин был из этого
family, the last, the last ruler from
рода последний последним правителем из
this family, Romano. Who was it, you can't swear, yeah,
этого из рода Романо Кто был ругаться же
yeah, okay, I won't. Well,
нельзя да да Ну хорошо не буду Ну
in my opinion, Lenin, I don't know, Lenin. Yes, I got it, well,
по-моему Ленин не знаю Ленин Да понял ну
he's Vladimir Ilyich Lenin. Yes, it's
он же Владимир Ильич Ленин Да это ж
Lenin - that's his nickname, like, party nickname.
Ленин - это его кличка типа партийная
And so he was Vladimir
так А так он был Владимир
Romanov, yeah, from Ulyanovsk. Yes, they knew that
Романов Угу из Ульяновска Да это знали
or guessed. And what's not, well, it's obvious, but it's
или угадали А что это не ну очевидно по
clearly not Stalin, that
что явно не Сталин что
he is. Well done, I know right. And why,
он да Молодец правильно знаю А почему
look, let's do it this way. Why was Lenin the
смотри давай так Почему Ленин был
last of the Romanov family, why didn't he
последним из рода Романовых почему он не
deprive
лишил наследников после
himself of heirs? I don't know. I'm saying I don't study history. I have
себя я не знаю я говорю историю не учу я
some facts that are out of place. Well, you
такие какие-то факты мимо Ну ты же
look. You look.  hung up This is this is the
Смотри ты ж ты ж повесил Вот это это это
flag Yes, which Lenin had hanging in his office
флаг Да который у Ленина в кабинете
Yes, when Stalin came, he hung it up like that Yes, that's what he
висел Да когда пришёл Сталин он зал так
wanted I
повешать Да вот Сто это захотел мне
liked it I just hung it up Stalin
понравилось Я повесил просто Сталин
came to power Yes, when he
пришёл когда к власти Да когда он
poisoned Lenin
отравил Ленина Да вот он э поменял
Yes, he
лю просто Когда Сталин пришёл Да он он
changed the flag to red and said everything and there will be
поменял флаг на красный и всё сказал и
blood like yes And Lenin He
будет кровь типа да А Ленин Вот у него
had this imperial flag like yes and by the
был вот этот имперский флаг типа да и
way I don't remember at first
там у него кстати я не помню сначала у
Lenin didn't write this We Russians are with us
Ленина не писалось вот это Мы русские с
God is like that and then in my opinion in
нами бог так а потом по-моему он в
yes by the
да
resolution of the Bolshevik Party Congress
постановлением съезда партии большевиков
[laughter]
[смех]
[music] the
[музыка]
main thing is to hang up the imperial flag yes We
главное по нацепить имперский флаг да Мы
Russians are with us God is like yes it was
русские с нами бог типа да
Lenin Ostanov from the
это Ленин был Остане из
Romanovs what are they like Damn I'm in
Романовых какие они ту просто Блин я в
shock Let's do it better Ivanka even
шоке Давай со круче неш Иванка даже
Hello Hello Where are you from I ca
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы откуда Вас
n't hear you
не слышно
Oh now I will hear oh now I can hear perfectly
О сейчас будет слышно о сейчас прекрасно
Where are you from How are you How is your health Where are
откуда Как ваше дела Как ваше здоровье
you
Вы
from Siberia Siberia I'm from the city
откуда Сибирь Сибирь Я из города
Khmelnitsky A Siberia where
Хмельницкий А Сибирь откуда
exactly Kemerovo region Kuzbass Kuzbass
именно Кемеровской область Кузбасс
Kuzbass my father
Кузбасс Кузбасс у меня отец
Novokuznetsk You from Novokuznetsk Yes
Новокузнецка Вы из Новокузнецка Да вы
what are you z My father is from Novokuznetsk oh
что з Отец мой из отец из Новокузнецка о
wonderful city And where are you
прекрасный город А вы
from I'm from near
откуда я из-под
Novokuznetsk cool imagine How did it
Новокузнецка прикольно представляете Как
happen the world is small sometimes yes and what do
совпала мир тесен бывает да а чём
you communicate with
общаетесь
Listen and to different different It depends on what kind of
Слушайте а разным разным Смотря какие
inadequate people you come across listen I
люди не адекваты попадаются слушайте
can discuss politics if necessary if
могу и политику обсудить если нужно если
people really want well they really want really want
люди прямо очень хотят ну нужно очень
But people don't accept
хотят Очень хотят Но люди не принимают
my point of view
моей точки зрения
Why did Russia attack
Почему Россия напала на
Ukraine did you read the Budapest
Украину вы читали будапештский
memorandum yes And what about the Lisbon
меморандум да И что лиссабонские
Lisbon agreement stop stop stop Let's have the
лиссабонское соглашение стоп стоп стоп
Budapest memorandum uh Who and to
Давайте будапештский меморандум э Кто и
whom Who and to whom gave guarantees under the
кому Кто и кому давал гарантии по
Budapest
будапештскому
memorandum let's start with the fact that it was an
меморандуму начнём с того что это был
agreement between several states
договор между несколькими государствами
Ukraine Russia Great Britain USA
Украина Россия Великобритания США
as far as we remember another one and I do
насколько Мы помним ещё одна а а ядерный
n't remember the nuclear one to be honest I don't
уже не вспомню если честно уже не
remember
вспомню
France France no  France was not there
Франция Франция нет Франции Там не было
100% Open clarify I can and no For
100% Откройте уточните Я могу и нет Я
some reason I am right that France was not there
почему-то у верно что Франции Там не
Ukraine Russia Great Britain and the USA
было Украина Россия Великобритания и США
ninety-fourth year as far as I
девяносто четвёртый год насколько я
remember December December in my opinion Yes
помню декабрь декабрь по-моему Да
Ukraine Russia Britain USA yes so Yes
Украина Россия Британия США да так А да
I already thought my memory fails super
я уже думал меня память подводит супер
so committed to Ukraine they so yes
так обязались перед Украиной они так да
let's put it in simple terms Ukraine decided to
давайте простым языком Украина решила
separate from the Soviet Union
отсоединиться от Советского Союза
correct No no no not so and a number of
правильно Нет нет нет не так и ряд
others no no not so No not Ukraine
других не не не так Нет не Украина
Let's start with the fact that Russia decided to
Давайте начнём с того что Россия решила
become a sovereign
стать суверенным
state remember here in your country Yeltsin
государством помните вот у вас же Ельцин
adopted on the 12th
принял 12
day of the year he
дено года
adopted a declaration
принял декларацию
of state sovereignty now
о Государственном суверенитете сейчас у
you still celebrate this
вас до сих пор празднуется это День
Russia Day yes what started the collapse of the Soviet
России да чем начал развал Советского
Union Well I don't
Союза Ну не
know Your Russians Yeltsin and Gorbachev
знаю Ваши русские Ельцин и Горбачёв
destroyed our Soviet Union which We
развалили Советский Союз наш который Мы
built Ukrainians Kazakhs Lithuanians Estonians
строили украинцы казахи литовцы эстонцы
all 15 republics built the Soviet Union
все 15 республик строили Советский Союз
Here you took it and destroyed it took the
Вот вы взяли развалили его забрали себе
factories for yourself took all the money from Sberbank
заводы забрали себе все деньги Сбербанка
that you had  still haven't paid
которые вы до сих пор не выплатили
deposits and
вклады и
that's it Well let's start Don't look not
всё Ну давайте начнём Не смотри не
Ukraine not Ukraine wanted to leave the
Украина не Украина захотела выйти из
Soviet Union but Russia Russia Okay Okay
Советского Союза а Россия Россия Да
so let's get back
хорошо Хорошо пусть так давайте вернёмся
to our to our affairs Budapest
к нашим к нашим делам будапештский
memorandum And what was its meaning that
меморандум И в чём был его смысл в том
countries countries guarantee
что страны страны гарантируют
yes
да
safety Before Ukraine, I think in the same
безопас Перед Укра по-моему в том же
year the
году был
Almaty declaration was signed
подписан Алматинская декларация
said which Ukraine signed
выговорил которую Украина подписала
remember this one again so Why did you
помните такую ещё раз так Почему вы
attack
напали на
Ukraine we didn't attack as we didn't cash in with the
Украину мы не напали как не нали
SZA
с сза
attacked we didn't say such a thing Where did you
напали мы не говорили такого Где вы
hear that someone from our Understand I
слышали чтобы кто-то из нашей Поня Я
accept this I accept this fight so
принимаю это я принимаю этот бой так
Okay so yes Well now Ukraine look is
Окей так да Ну сейчас Украина смотрите
conducting a special operation to demilitarize
проводит спецоперацию по демилитаризации
denazification of the Russian
денацификация Российской
Federation
Федерации
okay Yes because you illegally left the
хорошо Да потому что вы незаконно вышли
Soviet
из Советского
Union Let's speak based on the facts the
Союза Давайте по фактам говорить
declaration Ukraine signed you want a
декларацию Украина подписала вы хотите
fact
фак е
f fact you come on so Ukraine is a legitimate
ф факт вы давай так Украина легитимное
state it declared
государство оно провозгласило
independence on August 24 ninety-
независимость 24 августа девяносто
one when you declared
первого года когда вы провозгласили
independence where I don't
независимость куда не
hang out  I don't oh How about don't depend look come on
зависает я я не ой Как о не зави смотри
look explain Come on this way if the
давай смотри объясни Давай так если
Russian Federation is a non-existent
Российская Федерация несуществующий
entity if it exists When is your
субъект если существует Когда у вас День
Independence Day from the USSR
независимости от СССР
when How is it a non-existent
когда Как это не существующее
state Well if if when When was
государство Ну если если когда Когда
formed here was the state of the USSR
образовалось вот было государство СССР
Ukraine declared independence
Украина провозгласила независимость
what August ninety-first year
чего августа девяносто первого года
when did you declare independence from the
когда вы провозгласили независимость от
USSR Dava let you first answer
СССР Дава давайте вы сначала ответите на
my question which No I'll once
мой вопрос который Нет я ещ
again on the Almaty declaration then
раз по алматинскую декларацию значит
look
смотрите
ro federation is
ро федераци есть
invalid we do not recognize we do not
недействительными мы не признаём мы не
recognize because the state the state of the Russian Federation does
признаём потому что государство
not
государства Российская Федерация не
exist the state of the Russian
существует государство Российской
Federation does not exist Explain to me
Федерации не существует Объясни мне
tell me when the state of the
скажи когда появилось государство
Russian Federation appeared explain you yours
Российской Федерации объясни вы свае
explain Come on we conduct Yes as the
объясни Давай мы проводим Да как
Heirs of Kievan Rus we conduct
Наследники Киевской Руси проводим
denazification of the
денацификация
Federation as a temporary
Федерации как временного
geopolitical entity
геополитического образования которое
located on the lands of Great Tartary and
находится на землях Великой тартарии и
Great Rus' Let's explain to me if
великой Руси Давайте объясните мне если
you say that Russia
вы говорите что Россия что-то
signed something When the state of
подписывала Когда появилось государство
Russia appeared Here was the Soviet Union When
Россия Вот был Советский Союз Когда
Russia appeared Here was the Soviet
появилась Россия Вот был Советский
Union when when the date you yourself
Союз когда когда дата вы сами
want to chase me a question to my answer
хотите погонять ме вопрос на мой ответ
date look  let's talk or Do
дата смотри давай мся или Существуют ли
your state exist that something signed
ваше государство которое что-то подписва
my state appeared on October 24
моё государство появилось 24 октябр 24
August 24 ninety-one yours
августа девяносто первого года ваша
When it appeared cuts the right to you everything You
Когда появилось режет пра вам всё Ты
merge or you call When
сливаешь либо ты называешь Когда
your state appeared Either you
появилось ваше государство Либо вы
answer or you answer or go
отвечать либо ты отвечаешь либо идёшь
When your state appeared everything come on that's how you
Когда появилось ваше государство всё
need to talk to them
давай вот так с ними надо
Hello Exactly exactly
Здравствуйте Точно точно нас сейчас
how many of us are watching now millions uh
сколько смотрят миллионов ээ
1.700
1.700
million
миллионов
billion a billion Well, on our
миллиардов а миллиард Да ну у нас на
planet Well, how many do I think probably
планете Ну сколько мне кажется наверно
billion eight approximately but it's
миллиардов восемь ориентировочно но это
somewhere like that Okay, and what do you communicate with me even
где-то так Ладно а ч общаетесь мне даже
I got to you it seems on Stream What are you communicating about the EU I
я вам попал кажется на Стрим О чём ЕС
communicate about biology the idea is that I am a
общаюсь о биологии идея в том что я
zoologist I have 18 years of practice in 2
зоолог у меня 18 лет практика через 2
years will be the
года будет
twentieth anomalous biological
двадцатой аномальные биологические формы
life forms There is no biological life life
жизни Жизни биологические жизни нет
look
смотрите
Well there is
Ну есть
reincarnation What do you think there is no
реинкарнация Как вы думаете нет
reincarnation there is no such concept
реинкарнации нету такого понятия
look I explain
смотрите я я объясняю
look Let me explain to you I study
смотрите Давайте я вам объясню Я изучаю
Yes I study mutations samples problems
Да я изучаю проб мутации проблемы
mutations at
мутации при
crossing now my scientific work is the
скрещивания сейчас моя научная работа -
study of peak dogs and peak I do
это изучение пик догов а пик я такой
not know such work and mutation I know mutation
работы не знаю а мутация Я знаю мутация
for example there are Ninja Turtles they had a
например вот есть Черепашки Нинзя у них
mutation Well it's a cartoon yes they
была мутация Ну это мультик да они с
mutated look And your understanding
мутировали вот смотрите А ваше понима
what such a mutation Yes look I a little
что тако мутация Да смотрите Я немножко
about other
о других
cartoons yes And when
ция мультипликационных да А когда
for example two ra two different species
например скрещ два ра два разных вида
for example pigs and dogs yes you get peak
например пиги и доги да получается пик
dog and depending on the
дог и в зависимости от
proportion of chromosomes that came from a
пропорции хромосом которые попали от
pig or came from a dog yes you get one
пига или попали от дога да получается та
or another mutated entity but in
или иная мутированные сущность но в
general this class of mutants is called peak
общем этот класс мутантов называется пик
dogs No it's not a mutation this crossing is
доги Нет это не Мутация это скрещивание
called this crossing is called mutation
называется это скрещ называется
correctly look mutations there are
правильно мутация смотрите мутации есть
three types mutation mutation Turtles and
три вида мутация мутация Черепашки а
when they crossed it's a mutation And this
когда они перешли это мутация А это
is called crossing this crossing
называется скрещивание это скрещивание
is called crossing dogs cross crossing
называется скрещивают собак скрещ
Even even trees are crossed
скрещивают Даже даже деревья скрещивают
You won't believe it actually
Вы не поверите на самом деле
woo look I'm a biologist scow 18 years of
ву смотрите я вам как биолог скау 18 лет
practice in 2 years will be
практики через 2 года будет
twentieth continuation of the family in new persons
двадцатое продолжение рода в новых особ
certain mutations always
проходят определённые мутации всегда
always if you have a child he
всегда если у вас родится ребёнок у него
also has mutations that are different
также есть мутации чем-то отличающиеся
from you and also when crossing Yes new
от вас да также при скрещивании Да новых
children so there are mutations look No
детей так само есть мута смотрите Нет
look there are genetics
смотрите есть генетика
so look in the generation there can be for example for example
так смотрите поколении могут быть
I have for example my
например например у меня вот например
grandfather had cancer yes root ra okay there is
там дедушка болел раком да рути ра ладно
for example it's all genetic it's not
есть например это всё генетически это не
Mutation it's genetic it all happens
Мутация это генетически всё происходит
because there are generations 30 years
потому что есть поколения 30 лет
look look generation in
смотрите вот смотрите поколение на самом
fact you raised a generation you in
деле вот у вас вырастили поколение вы в
what Well in the Soviet Union you grew up
каком Ну в Советском Союзе выросли
look And there is a
смотрите А есть
mutation you mutate well how well how
мутация вы мутирует ну как вот ну как
become approximately I say this
становись ориентировочно это говорю
approximately in fact
Ориентировочно на самом деле
approximately and look and genetics and
ориентировочно и смотрите а генетика а
genetics genetics you have E we are Slavs we are
генетика генетика у вас Э мы славяне мы
Slavs you are not Slavs where are you
славяне вы не
from where are you from What
славяне вы откуда вы откуда С какой
region am I from Russia region What
области Я из России область Какая вы
Slav are you and I am a Slav You You from what
славянин и я славянин Вы Вы из какой
region am I from the Voronezh region
области Я из Воронежской области
Voronezh region sla I am a Slav
Воронежской области сла я славянин
look look Slavs Let's look look look
смотри смотри славяне Давай смотрю
here I have a book where the
смотри смотрю вот у меня есть книжка где
Slavs lived Look here there are
жили славяне Смотри вот есть
maps here maps where the Slavs
карты тут карты где жили славяне вот тут
lived here the Slavs lived you didn't have Slavs
жили славяне у тебя не жили славяне
Show the maps that in your Voronezh
Покажи карты что на твоей Воронежской
region the Slavs lived I live in the city of
области жили славяне Я живу в городе
Khmelnitsky look here the Slavs have
Хмельницкой смотри тут славяне от
always been born Look here the sixth
родяться были всегда Вот смотри шестой
sixth 7th century in the Soviet Union they did it
шестой 7 столетие в Советском Союзе ещё
until you falsified
сделали пока вы не фальсифицировали
history under Lenin
историю при Ленине
look here Look the Slavs lived here
посмотри сюда Посмотри славяне жили тут
the rivers Yuzhny Buk show everything Tell me
речки Южный бук всё покажи Расскажи
tell me at least one Slavic
расскажи мне хотя бы одно Славянское
settlement of the 7th century in the Voronezh region
Городище vii7 века в Воронежской области
run
бегом
said bem I won't tell you there in your
сказал бем я не скажу там у вас в
Voronezh region the Golden Horde ran
Воронежской области Золотая Орда бегала
principality what kind of Novgorod
княжество ты какой Новгородское
principality are you this is in Novgorod and not in your
княжество это в Новгороде а не в твоём
Voronezh to Novgorod Novgorod Slavs yes the
Воронеже в Новгород Новгород славяне да
Muscovite captured by you tell me in  your
захваченный Вами московит скажи в твоём
Voronezh where were the Slavs Tell me at least
Воронеже где были славяне Скажи хоть
one settlement of Slavs in the Voronezh
одно поселение славян в Воронежской
region Rus what city tell me what
области Русь какой город скажи какой
city in Rus was founded in Voronezh
город на Руси был основан в Воронеже
come on tell me Run What city in Rus did the
давай скажи мне Бегом Какой город на
Slavs organize in Voronezh
Руси славяне организовали в Воронеже
run come on 10th century look Vladimir
бегом давай X век смотри Владимир
baptized Rus someone says something Vladimir baptized
крестил Русь что-то говорит кто-то
Rus 988 what
Владимир крестил Русь 988 год какой у
city was yours Where is your city In
вас город был Где у вас город В каком
what city tell me 988 Prince Vladimir
каком город скажи 988 год князь Владимир
in Kyiv in Kyiv baptized and what
в Киеве в Киеве крестил а какой у вас
city was yours Voronezh What city was yours
город был Воронеже Какой у вас город был
in Voronezh yes Come on run
в Воронеже да А ну бегом
tell me Where did he baptize in Dne he baptized in
скажи А где он крестил в Дне он кре в
Dnieper And where was Dnieper And where was
Днепре А где был
Dnieper Where did he
Днепр А где это Днепр
baptize where he baptized not in Kyiv But
был Где крестил где крестил не в Киеве А
in
в
Dnieper in And now Now tell me Show
Днепре в А теперь Теперь скажи Покажи
me in your Voronezh at least one
мне вашем Воронеже хоть одну
Orthodox church of the tenth century come on
православную церковь десятого века давай
look how Come on come on no don't look I'm
смотри как Давай давай не не смотри я
telling you look at the maps where
тебе говорю смотри карты где жили
the Slavs lived We have I'm looking  here we
славяне У нас есть я тебе Смотри вот
dug up all the Slavs dug up everyone here
раскопали всех славян раскопали всех тут
we dug up where your Slavs are Show me
у нас раскопали где у вас славяне Покажи
man Where are your Slavs in the Voronezh
мужик Где у вас славяне в Воронежской
region
области
run and live Where are your Slavs in the
бегом сжи Где у вас славяне в
Voronezh region you are not a Slav
Воронежской области ты не славянин Ты
Look at yours Look at what you have
посмотри на сво Посмотри какой у тебя
You are real and now on the count of three go
Ты настоящий и теперь на счёт три идёшь
to
на
section 3 go
разд 3 пошл
Hello Hello Where are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
from Russia And where is Brussels
откуда Россия А куда Брюссель
How is Brussels
как
somewhere in Czechoslovakia Let's
гдето в Чехословакии
check
проверим
check it doesn't cover
проверьте не покрывает
some kind of crap and what to show what
чтото фигня какая-то а что показывать
nonsense what
что-что ерунду
I'm not interested I
какую Мне не интересно Я от фонаря
said the word Brussels out of nowhere I made it up I
сказал слово Брюссель я придумал такое Я
know that there is Brussels cabbage
знаю что капуста есть брюссельская
that's why I made it up Well I'm not
поэтому я так и придумал Ну я же не
saying that it shows nonsense No, it's your way of
говорю что ерунду показывает Да нету
speaking I
говор по вашему по вашему I по вашему IP
show some kind of nonsense according to your IP address I'm from the
адресу показывать какую-то лабуду Я из
city of Brno ate Brussels Priest Yes I'm from the
города бно ели Прист Брюсселя Да я из
city of Brno Brussels I made it up according to the
города Брно Брюссель Это я придумал по
name of the
названию
cabbage
капусты
Oh you grow cabbage No  I say I was a
О вы выращиваете капусту Нет я говорю я
child my mother gave me Brussels
в детстве мне мама давала брюссельскую
sprouts I came up with the city of Brussels just
капусту я придумал город Брюссель только
now I don't even know never heard of it
что вот я даже не знаю не слышал никогда
And so I'm from the city of Burno you know where the city of
А так я из города бурно знаете где город
Brno is not the same it's in Czechoslovakia just
Брно не тоже вот он в Чехословакии как
second after Prague Well
раз второй после Праги Ну наверное
probably probably in the Czech Republic or Slovakia They
наверное в Чехии или в Словакии Они же
sort of split up and dto Yes they split up
как бы разделились и дето Да разделились
but as if I was born I was still in
но как бы я родился ещё был в
Czechoslovakia that's why I'm like that dad
Чехословакии поэтому я так го папа
was a military man a military man was a
военный был военный военный был да
Soviet he served in this Western
Советский он Служил в этой Западной
Group of Forces Yes in the ZGV or something we were at
группе войск Да в згв что ли мы были
one time in Germany lived in the GDR And
были одно время в Германии жили в ГДР А
most of them are in
большинство в
Czechoslovakia And where is dad from dad is
Чехословакии А папа-то родом откуда папа
from Semipalatinsk
родом из Семипалатинска
in short there is a very confusing history
короче там очень Запутанная история у
he has Well I see and look at the city of Brno
него Ну понятно а посмотрите город Брно
Where
Где
is
находится
Bruno so Bruno
бруну так бруну
Oh something is somehow dense here Bern
Ой что-то тут как-то плотно всё Берн Да
No Brno I'll think of it Damn I'll just
нету Брно Я придумаю Блин я просто
come up with a name there is Bruno yes yes well there is
название придумаю на есть есть Бруно да
like Brno Well not Bruno  Brno
да ну есть как Брно Ну не Бруно Брно
a Brno just like that brn in German bruin
а Брно прям так брн по-немецки брюн
statutory city of the Czech Republic Well I
статутный город Чешской республики Ну я
I understood that Brno or Bruno Bruno is a
Я понял что Брно или Бруно Бруно - это
spiral which is first and not a
спираль такая есть которая в первую и не
spiral Bruno is military yes yes And I
спираль Бруно - это военная да да А я
thought Brno Well and Bruno is There is no such rn
думал Брно Ну а Бруно это Такого нет рна
yes And what is the city of Brno This is a joke How are
да А что есть город Брно Это прикол Като
you trolling
вы троллить
me Brno Yes how can this be brn
меня Брно Да как так может быть брн
such a name they wouldn't have come up with OJ
такое ну название не придумали бы ОЖ
awkward Well b b RN
неудобно Ну б б РН
o former German city it was called
о бывший город немецкий назывался он
bruin n
брюн н
n a now Czech
н а сейчас Чешской
Republic So what is this Do you know where the
республики Так что это А знаете где
city of
город
Osnabruck is again like
Оснабрюк ещё раз как
Osnabruck
Оснабрюк
Osnabruck No I don't know Well Google Osnabruck Osnabruck
Оснабрюк Нет не знаю А ну по гуглите
Osnabruck Germany
Оснабрюк Германия
correctly Germany And where is Germany
правильно Германия А где Германия
over there where it is located Oh so it's a decent
вон где он находится О так это приличный
city like not so small
город как бы такой не маленький
and the city of
а город
Aachen Burg is nearby like again
Аахен Бург рядом как ещё раз
Aachen
Аахен
Aa the names are also like that also
Аа названия такие тоже а тоже
Germany where it is
Германия он где
located
находится
Oh ah phe
так Ой а пхе
Achin simply or Achin it is written Achin and
Ахин просто или Ахин он пишется Ахин и
sometimes read Achin sometimes Achin
читается иногда Ахин иногда
But
Ахин А вот
it is not far from Dusseldorf and closer to
он недалеко от Дюссельдорфа а ближе к
Kln So now Oldenburg
кёль Так теперь Ольденбург
dial as
набирайте как
Oldenburg by And what am I dialing why
Ольденбург по А что я набираю зачем это
I dont know why I dial something I
я не знаю зачем что-то я Набираю
dial Yes its some kind of crap dial
набираю Да что-то фигня какая-то набери
this Dial that
это Набери
I think Why are you dialing Well
то я думаю Зачем ты набираешь Ну
okay I think its interesting to a person Maybe
ладно думаю человеку интересно Может
like Well
быть как бы
dial yours yourself as you said olf
Ну сам набирай свой как ты сказал ольф
olf
ольф
Brook Im closing Im thee
Брук закрываю Я
I have a press political men Come on Well
тея у меня прес полит мужи Да ладно Ну
what go What What kind of laugh is this
что го Что Что за смех
roulette My stomach is going to
рулетка У меня живот
burst Well why the hell isnt mine
лопнет Да ну нафиг что у меня-то не
bursting something
лопается что-то
funny Man Ill ask you now to
смешно Челове ели я сейчас попрошу Вас
dial some city
набрать город какой-нибудь там
somewhere I also want to laugh ask ask
где-нибудь мне что тоже смеяться
Why Lets play cities
попросите Зачем Давайте играем в города
You will each take turns we will
Вы будете каждый по очереди будем
name and dial its
называть и набирать
already kind of
уже вроде как бы
late somehow I dont feel like
поздно что-то как-то не тянет что-то в
playing this game well and  city Bratislava do you know
играть ну а город Братислава знаете
where Bratislava I heard it's the capital I
где Братислава слыхал это столица
think Slovaks
словаки слони
Slovenian Slovaks Czechoslovakia Slovakia Slovenia
Словении Чехословакия Словакии Словения
Slovaks Ponya Yes and what is the
словаки Поня Да а у Словении какая
capital of Slovenia Listen now in theory to laugh
столица Слушай сейс по идее рассмеяться
yes yes in Slovenia what is the
да да в Словении какая
capital I don't know love love
столица не знаю
blue Lyubava Lyubava Lyubava these are all
лю блю Любава Любава Любава это всё
vegetable gardens
огороды
Europe listen Question is You are a
Европа слушайте Вопрос такой Вы же
blogger No No Well well
блогер Да
because I've
нет А ну ну потому что что-то вы
come across you in this there with
попадались мне в этом вту там с
Russian bloggers what interests you
российскими блогерами что вас интересует
If I were a
Если бы я был
blogger a
блогером а
b What are you saying I didn't understand I was just
б Что вы говорите Не понял Я просто
saying that b Well you said and I say b
говорил что б Ну вы сказали а я говорю
No I was trying to tell you something you were
б Нет я пытался Вам что-то сказать вы
talking together with me but it doesn't
говорили вместе со мной а тут не
work out we are each other I I can't you are
получается мы друг друга я я не могу по
me zasha
вы меня заша
Yes Question Yes What do you
Да Вопрос Да Как вы
think the Americans will buy this Greenland
считаете вот эту гренландию американцы
or
купят или
not I think that Greenland will be
нет Я думаю что Гренландия будет
returned to its rightful owner
возвращена его законному владельцу
Norway and Greenland is
Норвегии а Гренландия - это
property ugh property I say
собственность фу собственность говорю
it used to belong to Norway
она раньше принадлежала Норвегии
Norway Yes now  occupied by Denmark in
Норвегии Да сейчас оккупирована Данией в
1839 after the Danish war it came under the
1839 году после датской войны отошла под
protectorate of the Kingdom of
протекторат королевства
Denmark that's why I
Дании вот я же поэтому и говор
first discovered the language the norm is the Norwegians under the
впервые открыли норма норвежские под
leadership of Olaf the Red well that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's why occupied by Denmark in 1839 after the Danish war it came under the protectorate of the Kingdom of Denmark that's why the language was first discovered the norm the Norwegians under the leadership of Olaf the Red that's that's that's that's that's that's that's that's why the
предводительством Олафа рыжего это ну
Danes don't want to
разрешение вот и всё датчане не хотят
give that because the Danes are with the British the Danes they have an
давать Да потому что датчане с
economic alliance with the British that's why they are
британцами экономический Да они ихний
developing their shelf the British Trump that's
шельф разрабатывают британцы Трамп вот
just a question of who will milk Greenland the
просто вопрос кто будет доить гренландию
British or the Americans if Trump
британцы или американцы если Трамп
pushes through that Greenland will be returned to
продавить что возвратить гренландию
Norway then the Americans will be there if it
Норвегии да тогда будут американцы Если
remains under the protectorate and then the British Yeah what do you
останется под протекторатом да и тогда
think well if we
британцы Угу А как вы считаете Ну если
assume that's ... that's that's why the Danes don't want to give that because the Danes are with the British the Danes they have an economic alliance with the British that's why they are developing their shelf the British Trump that'  this is a sell America the
предположим Вот это продат Америка
British will be offended by it Well look
британцы на неё обидятся Ну смотрите
British and if and if they
британцы и в том случае если и в том
sell will the British be offended by Do
случае если продают британцы обидятся ли
n't look British eh the British have
на Не смотрите британцы э британцы
always been offended by America because
отродясь обижены на Америку потому что
America is a former colony of Britain
Америка - это бывшая колония Британии
that rebelled against Britain and
которая восстала против Британии и
gained independence
обрела независимость
therefore the United States of America for
поэтому Соединённые Штаты Америки для
Britain is originally British
Британии это исконно британские
lands
земли
you understand Well let it be so this is how the
понимаете Ну пускай так это вот как
Soviet Union collapsed this is how the
распался Советский Союз так вот
Great British Empire collapsed
распалась Великая британская Империя
therefore the British They still have
поэтому британцы Они до сих пор у них
this sentiment for the restoration of the
есть это сентимент по восстановлению
British Empire its power that is
Британской Империи её могущество
more more understandable for you
у то есть более более понятно чтобы вам
there is such a term Anglo-Saxons I
было есть такой термин англосаксы Я
think you have heard Well yes yes yes that's it the
думаю вы слышали А ну да да та да вот
Anglo-Saxon world is a project of
это англосаксонский мир - это проект
globalism and world domination of the
глобалистика и мирового господства
Anglo-Saxon
англосаксонской
nation that is there are As if
нации то есть там идут Как бы
these Well squabbles yes Well
эти Ну тёрки да
as if yes The fact is that the
Ну как бы да Дело в том что
Anglo-Saxon elite it has
англосаксонская элита она имеет
some contradictions like you  in
некоторые противоречия вот как у вас в
Russia there is Prigozhin against Putin for
России там Пригожин против Путина
example what
например чего
[laughter]
[смех]
we are Moscow Moscow understood and the World Cup you are talking
мы Москва Москва понял а ЧМ общаетесь
here guys from
тут ребята из
Moscow about studying what are you somewhere
Москвы об учёбе вы что где-то
Schoolchildren not students students understood and the
Школьники не студенты студенты понял а
World Cup Well like And what about studying are you interested in
ЧМ Ну типа А что об учёбе Вас интересует
Who are you
На кого
studying to be
учитесь
historians cool In what century was Yuri
историки прикольно В каком веке был Юрий
Dolgoruky
Долгорукий
Dolgoruky 10th century 1147 year the foundation of
Долгорукий X век 1147 год основание
Moscow and in what year was the Pereslavl
Москвы а в ком году была переславская
Rada Well that very day when
рада Ну тот самый день когда
1654 did not ask and the Union was like a military no
1654 не попросил а Союз был типа военный
one asked yes it was like that Pony And in
никто не просил да был тако Поня А в
what year did Lenin create the Russian
каком году Ленин создал Российскую
Federation Lenin did not
Федерацию Ленин не
create Before that there was the Russian Empire
создавал До этого была Российская
fell apart it then Lenin
империя развалилась она потом Ленин
Russian Soviet Federative
Российская Советская Федеративная
Soviet is correct Yes yes which later
Советская правильно Да да которая потом
became the Russian Federation as the successor of the
стала Российской Федерацией как преемник
RSFSR that is Lenin invented you
РСФСР то есть вас придумал Ленин
correct Russia no no no Lenin did not
правильно Россия не не не Ленин нас не
invent us tell me And tell me as a historian when did the
придумал скажи А скажи как историк когда
Russians appear when the Russians
появились русские вот когда русские
began to be called
начали называться
Russians Wait can you
русскими Подожди а вы можете мне
answer me when the Ukrainians began to be called
ответить когда украинцы стали называться
See Look you are cutting out Come on answer
Видишь Смотри ты срезается Давай ответь
m to the question when did Russians appear
м на вопрос когда появились русские
when did they start to be called Russians Rus
когда начали называться русские
appeared in the world not Rus but
Русы появились в ве не Руссы а
Russians Russians are Rus Well look
русские русские есть Русы Ну вот смотри
earlier you weren't called earlier you were
раньше Вы не назывались раньше Вы
written as Great Russians Yes for example in the
писались великороссы Да например в
census of the Russian Empire there were no
переписи да Российской империи не было
Russians No when did they start calling you Here
русских Никаких когда же вас начали Вот
you are studying to be historians Yes you say yes
вы учитесь на историков Да вы говорите
when did you start to be called Russians
да когда вы начали называться русские
Russians from nowhere pos I don't know
русские из не откуда пось я не знаю
where from or not where but tell me look look first come on come on
откуда или не откуда но скажи смотри смо
look now the census I'll say
ични Давай давай смотри сейчас перепись
Give me no officially the
скажу Дайте нет официально
source
исто
census by the way So look look at the
перепись кстати говоря Значит смотри
census of the population of the Russian
смотри перепись население Российской
Empire in
империи
1897 there in black and white Yes it
1897 год вот там чёрным по белому Да
says
пишет
Great Russians No it's not written any
великороссы Не не написано никакие
Russians Wait listen again once
русские Подождите ещ раз прослушал ещ
again about the census of the population of the Russian
раз об перепись населения Российской
Empire in
империи
1897 exactly who provided
1897 год точ какой кто предоставил
this source what archive again here
данный источник какой архив ещё раз вот
officially you are taking Yes source now
официально берёте Да источник вот сейчас
google now Guys you are historians
гуглите сейчас Ребята вы историки
specific source I'm not asking you I'm
конкретный источник Я вас не прошу Я же
telling you source  source - this is the census of the
говорю источник источник - это перепись
Russian
населения Российской
Empire Okay Who compiled it Who
империи Хорошо Кто её составил Кто её
compiled it some imperial office
составил императорская какая-то контора
I don't know what it was like but look look
Я не знаю какая она была но смотри
open any take
смотри открываете любое вот берёте
now google any document and
сейчас гуглите любой документ и
show where it says Russians
показываете где там написано русские
Come on I'm
Давай я
waiting Well look there in the statistics there are
жду Ну смотри там там в статистике есть
Great Russians so good great Well yes God
великороссы так хорош велико Ну да Боже
really mo There are no Russians Well so when did you
реально мо Русских нет Ну так когда вы
start calling yourself Russians look well in
начали называться русскими смотри ну в
what year and who made the decision to
каком году и кто принял решение чтобы
call you with
назвать вас с
Russians no Good question tell me are you
русскими нет Вопрос хороший скажите вы
some kind of blogger Or are you just yes I am
блогер какой-то Или вы просто да я
some kind of
какой-то
blogger then tell me some blogger
блогер то скажите мне какому-то блогеру
yes when look I see the end of the 19th
да когда вот смотри я смотрю конец XIX
century does not write the
века не пишет в переписи населения
word Russians in the census of the Russian Empire no yes
Российской империи слова русские нету да
Now you call yourself Russians in the period of
Сейчас вы называете русские вот в период
1897 no Well look from the period of
1897 года не Ну смотри с периода 1897
1897 until now until
года до тепер до
2024 when it happened that you started
2024 когда случилось то что вы стали
calling yourself
называться
Russians no Wait su
русскими не Подождите су
po That is, it turns out that either Lenin
по То есть получается это либо Ленин
or Stalin came up with Russians  Call
либо Сталин придумал русскими Называть
you yes this is
вас это
nano
нано
pony this is
пони этова
soze Yes you started to be called Russians, that's how
созе Да вас начали называть русскими так
I
я
understand it, well, just like Ukrainians started to be
понимаю ну так же как и украинцев стали
called Ukrain Look, I'm asking you
называть Украин Смотри я тебя спрашиваю
yes, that is, I understand correctly Yes, what
да то есть я правильно понимаю Да что
else in the 10th century were you not
ещё в X веке вы русскими не
called Russians at that time no,
назывались на тот момент нет мы
we were called earlier how is it earlier how is it earlier that is,
есть вы назывались раньше русскими потом
you were called Russians earlier then they stopped
вас перестали называть русскими потом
calling you Russians then they started calling you Russians again something you're
снова стали называть русскими что-то вы
confusing the testimony When you were called
путаете показания Когда вы назывались
Russians For example, you
русскими Вот например
can T I he was written that he had a type of
можете Т I он писался что у него типа
subject
подданный
Russians but wait And do you know how PT
русские а подождите А вы в курсе как ПТ
I was designated in European documents
I обозначался в европейских документах
once again not European as he
ещ раз не европейских как он сам себя
designated himself once again [ __ ] No No No
обозначал ещ раз ещ раз сри Нет Нет Нет
look come on don't tell these fables
смотрите давай не надо вот эти басни
you ska
расска ты ска
from va vo no once again I I don't know
от ва во нет ещ раз я я не знаю
European documents I'm not European Yes I'm a
европейские документы я не европеец Да я
Ukrainian here you are Russians Yes we
вот украинец тут вы россияне Да вот мы
live here Let's look in our
тут живём Давайте смотрите в наших
Ukrainian historical documents he
украинских исторических документах он не
was not Russian in Russian documents he
был русским в российских документах он
was not Russian then tell me what
не был русским то скажи как называл себя
Peter I called himself all
Пётр I всё
historians so Russians invented Lenin with
историки так русских придумал Ленин со
Stalin subscribe to the new
Сталина подпишись на новый
channel on y Telegram right now axis VN
канал на й Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show to people at times do not
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams That is why for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
us Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
written right now and while there in telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm videos there is also interesting and useful
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we owe you
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
constant operational links
постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
write N
пиши N